&gt;&gt; In 2014, Google published its own network in
— 2014 年 谷歌在 ImageNet 竞赛中
the ImageNet competition and in homage to Yann LeCun and LeNet,
发布了自己的网络 为了向 Yann LeCun 的 LeNet 致敬
Google named their network,
谷歌很巧妙地把该网络命名为
wait for it, GoogLeNet.
慢慢念： GoogLeNet
It's spelled like GoogleNet but it's pronounced GoogLeNet.
它融合了 Google 和 Net 这两个词 但发音为 GoogLeNet
Go figure.
下面看图
In the ImageNet competition,
在 ImageNet 竞赛中
GoogLeNet performed even a little better than VGG:
GoogLeNet 的表现甚至比 VGG 略胜一筹
6.7% compared to 7.3% percent,
其错误率仅为 6.7% 而 VGG 则为 7.3%
although at that level,
当然 如此接近的成绩
it kind of feels like we're splitting hairs.
也算是平分秋色了
&gt;&gt; GoogLeNet's great advantage is that it runs really fast.
— GoogLeNet 的主要优势在于它的运行速度非常快
The team that developed GoogLeNet developed a clever concept
它的研发团队提出了一个很聪明的概念
called an Inception module, which trains really well and is efficiently deployable.
称为 Inception 模块 这个模块使得训练效果更好 部署效率也很高
&gt;&gt; Do you remember inception?
— 你还记得 Inception 模块吗？
Vincent explained the concept earlier.
Vincent 前面解释过这个概念
We're going to show it again here, in case you forgot.
让我们再复习一下
&gt;&gt; It's called an inception module.
— 这是一个 Inception 模块
It's going to look a little more complicated.
它看上去比较复杂一些
The idea is that at each layer of your ConvNet,
它的原理是 在你的卷积网络的每一层
you can make a choice,
你可以选择进
have a pooling operation,
行池化运算
have a convolution and then you need to decide,
卷积运算
is it the one by one convolution or a three by three or five by five.
如果是卷积 那么大小应该是 1×1、3×3 还是 5×5
All of these are actually beneficial to the modeling power of your network.
其实这些对网络的建模能力都是有益的
So why choose? Let's use them all.
所以何必还要选呢？ 把它们全部用上就好了
Here's what an inception module looks like.
Inception 模块看起来这个样子
Instead of having a single convolution,
它不局限于单个卷积运算
you have a composition of average pooling followed by one by one,
而是将多个模块组合
then a one by one convolution,
如平均池化后接 1×1 的卷积
then a one by one followed by a three by three,
单独的 1×1 的卷积 接着 3×3 的卷积
then a one by one followed by a five by five and
另一个 1×1 的卷积 接着 5×5 的卷积
at the top you simply concatenate the output of each of them.
最后把这些运算的输出连成一串
It looks complicated but what's interesting is that you can choose these parameters
它看起来很复杂 但有趣的是 根据你选择参数的方式
in such a way that the total number of parameters in your model is very small,
模型中的参数总数可能非常少
yet the model performs better than if you had a simple convolution.
但模型的性能比你使用简单卷积时要好
&gt;&gt; As Vincent says, the inception modules create
— 就像 Vincent 说的
a situation in which the total number of parameters is very small.
Inception 模块可以使网络的参数总数非常少
This is why GoogLeNet runs almost as fast as AlexNet.
这就是 GoogLeNet 运行速度接近于 AlexNet 的原因
&gt;&gt; And of course GoogLeNet has great accuracy.
— 当然 GoogLeNet 的识别准确率也非常高
Like we mentioned earlier,
我们前面提到过
it's ImageNet error was only 7%.
它在 ImageNet 上的错误率只有 7% 左右
GoogLeNet is a great choice to investigate if you need to run your network in real time,
如果你需要一个实时运行网络 那么 GoogLeNet 是一个理想选择
like maybe in a self-driving car.
无人车就是一个很好的应用实例